Contact

kdcaldwell2@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/kristen-caldwell-a9a20b89 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Nursing
Healthcare
Clinical Research

Kristen Caldwell

Fulltime Student at United States Air Force

Colorado Springs, Colorado

Summary

Experienced Clinical Coordinator with a demonstrated history of working in the Hospital & Health Care industry. Skilled in Emergency Management, Administration, Healthcare, Medicine, and Cardiopulmonary Resuscitation (CPR). Strong healthcare services professional with a Master of Arts - MA focused in Human Services Counseling-Crisis Response and Trauma from Liberty University.

Experience

United States Air Force
7 years 9 months
Fulltime Student
August 2019 - Present (11 months)
Denver, Colorado, United States

Patient Movement Clinical Coordinator October 2012 - Present (7 years 9 months) Hickam AFB, HI

A Patient Movement Clinical Coordinator (PMCC) develops patient movement operation strategies that support medical regulating and validation services for the Pacific theater's more than 450,000 DoD beneficiaries. PMCCs in the Pacific theater work as an Aeromedical Evacuation (AE) liaisons for 50 DoD/civilian healthcare organizations and agencies, and as shift leader for 8 joint NCO's. PMCCs are theater experts for the TRAC2ES program execution and joint MTF training to facilitate seamless en route care for over 3,600 patients per year. They also direct USTRANSCOM's AE Patient Safety Program for PACOM and provides joint strategic and exercise clinical planning support.

Usaf Medical Center
Flight Commander
April 2016 - Present (4 years 3 months)
Colorado Springs, Colorado Area

Flight Commander of Operational Medicine at USAFA

United States Air Force 5 years 2 months Flight Nurse August 2009 - August 2012 (3 years 1 month)

Ramstein AB, Germany

Member of the Aeromedical Evacuation (AE) crew. Functions as the senior medical member of the AE team during CONUS, intra-theater, and intertheater flights. Collaborates with appropriate agencies and personnel concerned with conduct of the mission.

Plans and prepares for AE missions. Coordinates with the operational aircrew and mission pre-planning. Prepares patient positioning plan to facilitate patient enplaning, nursing care, comfort, and safety. Evaluates individual patient's inflight needs and requests appropriate medications, supplies, and equipment. Supervises enplaning and securing of patients. Prepares and maintains plan for patient evacuation from aircraft in case of an aircraft emergency.

Plans and provides in-flight patient care. Provides continuing nursing care from originating to destination facilities. Monitors and evaluates patient condition and reactions to stresses of flight and initiates appropriate interventions as needed. Maintains and annotates in-flight patient records. Acts as liaison between medical and operational aircrews and support personnel in order to promote patient safety and comfort and to accomplish the mission. Maintains and completes data on forms relative to the mission. Supervises deplaning of patients and off-loading of patient baggage, supplies, and equipment. Briefs medical personnel at receiving medical facility on continuing nursing care and requirements. Accompanies patient to receiving medical facility when appropriate.

Provides emergency care. Initiates emergency interventions for in-flight medical emergencies. Provides emergency care to patients in the event of an aircraft emergency, wheels-up landing, ditching, rapid decompression, or fuselage fire.

Participates in nursing service administration activities. Participates in the instruction and evaluation of in-flight nursing care routines and practices.

Med/Surg RN July 2007 - July 2009 (2 years 1 month) Provides comprehensive and specialty nursing care. Assesses health and health care needs of individuals and populations. Collects, records, and analyzes patient or population health data from preventive health assessments, nursing history, physical examinations and other sources. Uses data to determine nursing needs of patients/populations. Identifies expected health outcomes. Involves the patient, family, and community in setting realistic goals to achieve desired outcomes. Plans comprehensive care attains expected outcomes. Collaborates with other disciplines. Implements and evaluates nursing interventions. Conducts group and individual health teaching for patients, families, and community. Monitors and records patient and population health status. Uses ongoing assessment data to evaluate progress toward expected outcomes and revise plan of care as needed. Documents nursing actions and activities.

University of Kansas Medical Center Staff RN May 2006 - February 2007 (10 months) Kansas City, Kansas

Cardiovascular Progressive Care RN

Education

Liberty University

Master of Arts - MA, Human Services Counseling-Crisis Response and Trauma · (2016 - 2018)

University of Missouri-Kansas City
Bachelor's degree, Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse · (2000 - 2006)

University of Missouri-Kansas City
Bachelor of Science, Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse · (2000 - 2006)